<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring on Crunchy PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</title>
    <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.2/installation/metrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring on Crunchy PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.2/installation/metrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Prerequisites</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.2/installation/metrics/metrics-prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.2/installation/metrics/metrics-prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites The following is required prior to installing PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring.
Environment PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring is tested in the following environments:
 Kubernetes v1.13+ Red Hat OpenShift v3.11+ Red Hat OpenShift v4.3+ VMWare Enterprise PKS 1.3+  Application Ports The PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring installer deploys different services as needed to support PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring collection and monitoring. Below is a list of the applications and their default Service ports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.2/installation/metrics/postgres-operator-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.2/installation/metrics/postgres-operator-metrics/</guid>
      <description>PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring Installer Quickstart If you believe that all the default settings in the installation manifest work for you, you can take a chance by running the metrics manifest directly from the repository:
kubectl create namespace pgo kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CrunchyData/postgres-operator/v4.5.2/installers/metrics/kubectl/postgres-operator-metrics.yml  However, we still advise that you read onward to see how to properly configure the PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring infrastructure.
Overview The PostgreSQL Operator comes with a container called pgo-deployer which handles a variety of lifecycle actions for the PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring infrastructure, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Configuration Reference</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.2/installation/metrics/metrics-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.2/installation/metrics/metrics-configuration/</guid>
      <description>PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring Installer Configuration When installing the PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring infrastructure you have various configuration options available, which are defined below.
General Configuration These variables affect the general configuration of PostgreSQL Operator Monitoring.
   Name Default Required Description     alertmanager_log_level info  Set the log level for Alertmanager logging.   alertmanager_service_type ClusterIP Required How to expose the Alertmanager service.   alertmanager_storage_access_mode ReadWriteOnce Required Set to the access mode used by the configured storage class for Alertmanager persistent volumes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>