<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other Methods on Crunchy PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</title>
    <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other Methods on Crunchy PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Scripts</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/bash/</guid>
      <description>A full installation of the Operator includes the following steps:
 create a project structure configure your environment variables configure Operator templates create security resources deploy the operator install pgo CLI (end user command tool)  Operator end-users are only required to install the pgo CLI client on their host and can skip the server-side installation steps. pgo CLI clients are provided for Linux, Mac, and Windows clients.
The Operator can be deployed by multiple methods including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helm Chart</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/helm/</guid>
      <description>The PostgreSQL Operator Helm Chart Overview The PostgreSQL Operator comes with a container called pgo-deployer which handles a variety of lifecycle actions for the PostgreSQL Operator, including:
 Installation Upgrading Uninstallation  After configuring the values.yaml file with you configuration options, the installer will be run using the helm command line tool and takes care of setting up all of the objects required to run the PostgreSQL Operator.
The postgres-operator Helm chart is available in the Helm directory in the PostgreSQL Operator repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Cloud Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/google-cloud-marketplace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/google-cloud-marketplace/</guid>
      <description>The PostgreSQL Operator is installed as part of Crunchy PostgreSQL for GKE that is available in the Google Cloud Marketplace.
Step 1: Install Install Crunchy PostgreSQL for GKE to a Google Kubernetes Engine cluster using Google Cloud Marketplace.
Step 2: Verify Installation Install kubectl using the gcloud components command of the Google Cloud SDK or by following the Kubernetes documentation.
Using the gcloud utility, ensure you are logged into the GKE cluster in which you installed the PostgreSQL Operator, and see that it is running in the namespace in which you installed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OperatorHub.io</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/operator-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.5.1/installation/other/operator-hub/</guid>
      <description>If your Kubernetes cluster is already running the Operator Lifecycle Manager, the PostgreSQL Operator can be installed as part of Crunchy PostgreSQL for Kubernetes that is available in OperatorHub.io.
Before You Begin There are a few manual steps that the cluster administrator must perform prior to installing the PostgreSQL Operator. At the very least, it must be provided with an initial configuration.
First, make sure OLM and the OperatorHub.io catalog are installed by running kubectl get CatalogSources --all-namespaces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>