<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation on PGO: PostgreSQL Operator from Crunchy Data Documentation</title>
    <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation on PGO: PostgreSQL Operator from Crunchy Data Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisites</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites The following is required prior to installing PGO.
Environment PGO is tested in the following environments:
 Kubernetes v1.13+ Red Hat OpenShift v3.11+ Red Hat OpenShift v4.4+ Amazon EKS VMWare Enterprise PKS 1.3+ IBM Cloud Pak Data  IBM Cloud Pak Data If you install PGO, which comes with Crunchy PostgreSQL for Kubernetes, on IBM Cloud Pak Data, please note the following additional requirements:
 Cloud Pak Data Version 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install PGO the Postgres Operator</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/postgres-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/postgres-operator/</guid>
      <description>PGO: Postgres Operator Installer Quickstart If you believe that all the default settings in the installation manifest work for you, you can take a chance by running the manifest directly from the repository:
kubectl create namespace pgo kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CrunchyData/postgres-operator/v4.6.3/installers/kubectl/postgres-operator.yml  However, we still advise that you read onward to see how to properly configure the PostgreSQL Operator.
Overview PGO comes with a container called pgo-deployer which handles a variety of lifecycle actions for the Postgres Operator, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install &#34;pgo&#34; Client</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/pgo-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/pgo-client/</guid>
      <description>Install the PostgreSQL Operator (pgo) Client The following will install and configure the pgo client on all systems. For the purpose of these instructions it&amp;rsquo;s assumed that PGO: the Postgres Operator from Crunchy Data is already deployed.
Prerequisites  For Kubernetes deployments: kubectl configured to communicate with Kubernetes For OpenShift deployments: oc configured to communicate with OpenShift  To authenticate with the PGO API:
 Client CA Certificate Client TLS Certificate Client Key pgouser file containing &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;  All of the requirements above should be obtained from an administrator who installed PGO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Reference</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/4.6.3/installation/configuration/</guid>
      <description>PGO Installer Configuration When installing PGO, the Postgres Operator you have many configuration options, these options are listed in this section.
General Configuration These variables affect the general configuration of the PostgreSQL Operator.
   Name Default Required Description     archive_mode true Required Set to true enable archive logging on all newly created clusters.   archive_timeout 60 Required Set to a value in seconds to configure the timeout threshold for archiving.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>