<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</title>
    <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation on Crunchy Data PostgreSQL Operator Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisites</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites The following is required prior to installing PostgreSQL Operator.
Environment The PostgreSQL Operator is tested in the following environments:
 Kubernetes v1.13+ Red Hat OpenShift v3.11+ Red Hat OpenShift v4.3+ VMWare Enterprise PKS 1.3+ IBM Cloud Pak Data  IBM Cloud Pak Data If you install the PostgreSQL Operator, which comes with Crunchy PostgreSQL for Kubernetes, on IBM Cloud Pak Data, please note the following additional requirements:
 Cloud Pak Data Version 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install the PostgreSQL Operator</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/postgres-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/postgres-operator/</guid>
      <description>The PostgreSQL Operator Installer Quickstart If you believe that all the default settings in the installation manifest work for you, you can take a chance by running the manifest directly from the repository:
kubectl create namespace pgo kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CrunchyData/postgres-operator/master/installers/kubectl/postgres-operator.yml  However, we still advise that you read onward to see how to properly configure the PostgreSQL Operator.
Overview The PostgreSQL Operator comes with a container called pgo-deployer which handles a variety of lifecycle actions for the PostgreSQL Operator, including:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install `pgo` Client</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/pgo-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/pgo-client/</guid>
      <description>Install the PostgreSQL Operator (pgo) Client The following will install and configure the pgo client on all systems. For the purpose of these instructions it&amp;rsquo;s assumed that the Crunchy PostgreSQL Operator is already deployed.
Prerequisites  For Kubernetes deployments: kubectl configured to communicate with Kubernetes For OpenShift deployments: oc configured to communicate with OpenShift  The Crunchy Postgres Operator als requires the following in order to authenticate with the apiserver:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Reference</title>
      <link>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crunchydata.github.io/postgres-operator/stable/installation/configuration/</guid>
      <description>PostgreSQL Operator Installer Configuration The pgo-deployer container is launched by using a Kubernetes Job manifest and contains many configurable options.
This section lists the options that you can configure to deploy the PostgreSQL Operator in your environment. The following list of environmental variables can be used in the postgres-operator.yml manifest.
General Configuration These environmental variables affect the general configuration of the PostgreSQL Operator.
   Name Default Required Description     ARCHIVE_MODE true Required Set to true enable archive logging on all newly created clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>